<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maths on </title>
    <link>/categories/maths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maths on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/maths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>/post/fast-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fast-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static asdsdswd Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior and Posterior distributions</title>
      <link>/post/prior-and-posterior-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/prior-and-posterior-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Let´s suppose that we know all the possible causes for an outcome, for example:
**
Bayes theorem Posterior = ( Likelihood * Prior ) / Evidence
Here, P(movie|Sci-fi) is called Posterior, P(Sci-fi|Movie) is Likelihood, P(movie) is Prior, P(Sci-fi) is Evidence.
Prior: How probable was our hypothesis before observing the evidence? Posterior: How probable is our hypothesis given the observed evidence? Evidence: How probable is the new evidence under all possible hypotheses?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic probability concepts</title>
      <link>/post/basic-probability-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/basic-probability-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this series of articles, We&amp;rsquo;ll dig deep into understanding Bayesian inference, starting from the basics.
The main idea behind Bayesian statistics is the Bayes theorem, we need to understand some concepts first.
Concepts Let´s illustrate these concepts with poker cards and rolling dices:
 An experiment is a well-defined action, that might result in a number of outcomes. Outcome: Possible result of an experiment. Each outcome is unique, and different outcomes are mutually exclusive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>