<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maths on </title>
    <link>https://www.danielsobrado.com/categories/maths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maths on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielsobrado.com/categories/maths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Linear Regression  A linear regression tries to estimate a linear relationship that best fits a given set of data.
 We need to understand that Linear Regression won´t help us with non linear relationships.
When we do a regression we are trying to understand the strength and direction of the relationship between two or more variables.
This is different from correlation analysis, because the model allows us to infer on new inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/fast-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/fast-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static asdsdswd Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naive Bayes</title>
      <link>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/naive-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/naive-bayes/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Naive Bayes Types of Naive Bayes Algorithms Gaussian Naive Bayes We assume that each class has continuos Normal/Gaussian distributed values.
MultiNomial Naive Bayes Bernoulli Naive Bayes Advantages and Disadvantages Advantages Disadvantages </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior and Posterior distributions</title>
      <link>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/prior-and-posterior-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/prior-and-posterior-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Let´s suppose that we know all the possible causes for an outcome, for example:
**
Bayes theorem Posterior = ( Likelihood * Prior ) / Evidence
Here, P(movie|Sci-fi) is called Posterior, P(Sci-fi|Movie) is Likelihood, P(movie) is Prior, P(Sci-fi) is Evidence.
Prior: How probable was our hypothesis before observing the evidence? Posterior: How probable is our hypothesis given the observed evidence? Evidence: How probable is the new evidence under all possible hypotheses?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic probability concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/basic-probability-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielsobrado.com/post/basic-probability-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this series of articles, We&amp;rsquo;ll dig deep into understanding Bayesian inference, starting from the basics.
The main idea behind Bayesian statistics is the Bayes theorem, we need to understand some concepts first.
TL;DR Let´s take the following poker cards as an example:
Our experiment is to take two cards for the deck, one at a time, each card extraction is an event. We define as outcomes that a card is of a defined</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>