<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Spark: Introduction to project Tungsten</title>
      <link>/post/apache-spark-introduction-to-project-tungsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/apache-spark-introduction-to-project-tungsten/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow vs Pytorch: Basics</title>
      <link>/post/tensorflow-vs-pytorch-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tensorflow-vs-pytorch-basics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The best why to learn a framework is to learn two at the same time and compare how things are being achieved in different ways, understanding advantages and disadvantages.
Tensorflow and Pytorch are frameworks for fast tensor manipulation that is what is required for deep learning and some other machine learning methods.
Both heavily oriented towards machine learning and specially deep learning are low level libraries to operate on tensors (n-dimensional arrays).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle: Mercari competition</title>
      <link>/post/kaggle-mercari-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kaggle-mercari-competition/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Goto hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>/post/fast-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fast-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static asdsdswd Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Data Science: Concepts</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-data-science-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-data-science-concepts/</guid>
      <description> So many new concepts for the beginner data scentist, let´s start one by one:
Tensor A tensor is a generalized matrix, it is defined by his rank, a rank zero tensor, is just a number, while a rank two tensor is a two dimensional matrix or array.
See: What’s the difference between a matrix and a tensor?
Features </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scipy: Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/scipy-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scipy-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic probability concepts</title>
      <link>/post/basic-probability-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/basic-probability-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static asdsdswd Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numpy: Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/numpy-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/numpy-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Numpy is the fundation of scientific computing in Python.
Installing Numpy There are a few concepts that you need to understand before creating a theme.
Numpy Arrays ndarray is the earth of NumPy, it&amp;rsquo;s the main data storage object of the framework.
Why do we need other arrays? We have Python lists and dictionaries,
We can use the %timeit magic command in IPython to test the performance
ndarrays are fast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi!, I´m Daniel, originally from northern Spain and currently residing in Abu Dhabi.
I enjoy traveling. Each and every time, I find something magical about having a new stamp on my passport. Apart from experiencing the beauty of a new place, I enjoy the experience wherein I get to meet new people, learn about their culture and traditions, and thus expand my level of awareness to level higher.
Learning through travel changes you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS: Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/angularjs-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/angularjs-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction All started when I started developping some quick reconcialition tool for the bank´s Product Control team, someone said: &amp;ldquo;Hey Daniel, can you help us with this? Take this and that and apply this rules and give us the results on something we can visualize, it is too much data for excel!
I love solving issues for my business partners and I immediately started rolling my sleaves, things look simple and easy at the begining but the reality sometimes is different, I had a to use a large database to transform the data, this triggered a proper project and many gobernance procedures, like authentication, authorization, chinese walls, user management etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worldbank datasets: Jobs and economic indicators</title>
      <link>/post/worldbank-datasets-jobs-and-economic-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/worldbank-datasets-jobs-and-economic-indicators/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>